It's been ten years
大贤者
since Great Sage Alabaster first uttered the prophecy.
自从阿拉巴斯塔大人预言过后 已经过了十年
The day has finally come.
我们不知道等待这一天多久了
Almost there...
还差一点点
What is that?
怎么了
What is going on?
这是什么
Aliens?
宇宙人
A girl?
女孩子
May I know your name?
你叫什么名字
Me? I'm Satou.
我…我叫佐藤
I see.
这样啊
It's an unusual name.
好奇特的名字
My name is Nokana... You can call me Hime.
我的名字叫诺卡那…公主
Hime?
公主?
Satou.
佐藤
You must tell anyone about what you saw here.
你不能把在这里看到的事情 告诉任何人
It's better for you to simply forget it.
倒不如说请你忘记吧
In return,
作为交换 我会…
I'll be your friend.
成为你的朋友
I was a little boy back then.
这时候的我
Despite that,
虽然年纪还小却想着
I knew I had to protect her.
我必须保护她
I will carry that thought until the end of time.
并认为这件事一定会持续到永远
TALES OF WEDDING RINGS
《婚戒物语》
TEN YEARS LATER
(10年后)
Good morning, Satou.
早安 佐藤
Hime.
小姬…
Good morning.
早安
I made you breakfast.
早餐做好了哦
This is a bit overkill for breakfast.
一大早就吃这么丰盛
After today, it's summer break.
因为今天过完 学校就放假
I woke up early without realising it.
所以我不自觉早起了
Hime.
小姬…
Hime Nonaka is my childhood friend.
野中姬乃是我的青梅竹马
It's been ten years since they moved into the house next door.
他们搬到我家隔壁正好是十年前
I think her parents are out of the picture.
她好像没有父母
She lives only with Gramps.
和爷爷两个人一起生活
You've changed a lot ever since you started high school.
小姬你上了高中之后就变了呢
You used to be very bashful.
以前明明更腼腆的
I'd draw more attention to myself
因为刻意保持低调
if I intentionally kept a low profile,
反而会更引人注目
given my unique hair colour.
头发又是这种颜色
Besides, I'm a princess.
再说我是公主
It's crucial for me to be strong.
必须坚强才行
You've been saying that since we were kids.
你好像从以前就一直在说这件事
What?
什么事
Hime...
小姬…
I got it for you.
沾到了
Gramps.
爷爷
Good morning, Gramps.
小姬的爷爷 早安
Good morning, Satou.
早安 佐藤
We're headed out.
我们出门了
Stay safe.
路上小心
Is your father coming back?
你爸爸还没有回来吗
He won't be back until after summer break.
暑假结束前应该都不会回来
It must be tough.
真辛苦呢
I'm used to it.
我已经习惯了
This ring
这只戒指
is meant for the man I'll marry someday. It means a lot to me.
是送给以后结婚对象的重要东西
Satou.
佐藤
Will you marry me when we grow up?
你长大之后要不要和我结婚
What are you looking at?
看什么
You're never getting this.
我不会给你的
This ring is very important to me.
因为这是很重要的东西
Whatever, a childhood promise
算了 小时候的约定
shouldn't be taken seriously.
也不过如此而已
Hurry up. We're going to be late.
不快点会迟到哦
Coming!
来了
How did you do in the finals?
期末考考得怎么样
My grades are terrible.
超烂的
Check this out!
你们看
Impressive, Hime! It must be nice to be smart.
不愧是小姬 你好聪明
As a princess, it's my duty to be smart.
公主当然要会念书啦
There you go again.
你又在说这种话
Which country's princess are you anyway?
所以你到底是哪国的公主啊
Summer break begins tomorrow!
从明天开始就放暑假了耶
I envy you, Satou. You don't feel the stress at all.
真羡慕佐藤 感觉真从容
Having a girlfriend is so much better.
有女朋友的人果然不同
You know I mean Nonaka!
就是野中同学啊
You come to school together every day!
你们不是每天都一起上学吗
That's only because she lives next door.
那只是因为我们是邻居啦
You know,
我说你
things won't stay the same forever.
可别以为能永远像现在这样哦
Yeah.
就是啊
Don't come begging for help when you lose her one day.
要是哪天为时已晚 我可不管你
I'd start dating her immediately
那么可爱的女生
because of how cute she is.
换作是我 一定会马上跟她交往
"LET'S GO TO THE SUMMER FESTIVAL LATER" No, I don't like that.
(今天放学后去参加夏季庆典) 不 我不太喜欢那种花俏的女生
"MEET UP IN FRONT OF THE SHRINE AT 6 PM" She is too flashy.
(6点半在神社前会合)
-Why is she texting me? -So, what is your type, then?
-为什么要特地传信息… -那不然你喜欢什么样的类型
I prefer the more reserved and innocent type.
我比较喜欢保守一点 感觉很清纯的女生
-Wait... It wouldn't harm to have hope! -There you go, the reserved and innocent.
-不…稍微期待一下也可以吧 -出现了 保守又清纯的类型
Hime!
小姬
A yukata?
浴衣…
What's wrong?
怎样
Are you mesmerised by my charm?
把你迷倒了吗
Yeah.
是啊
That's... That's very honest of you.
你…你这个人真诚实呢
All right. Let's go.
好了 我们走吧
Okay.
好
COTTON CANDY, BUTTER POTATO
(棉花糖 奶油土豆)
"BBQ, TAKOYAKI" This place is neat!
(什锦烧 章鱼烧) 果然很棒
Festivals never fail to get me excited.
庆典这种活动真令人兴奋
Satou.
佐藤
Do you remember?
你还记得吗
When we were kids, we got lost in the festival.
小时候我们曾经一起 在这里举行的庆典里迷路
You said we shouldn't get separated,
你说我们两个人不能走散
so you held my hand the whole time.
所以一直牵着我的手对吧
You were so cool back in the days.
你那时候明明很帅气的
Am I not cool now?
现在就不帅了吗
What do you think?
你说呢
Anyway, let's grab some food.
总之我们先去吃点东西吧
They are so cute!
好可爱
Are... Are you serious?
可…可爱吗
It's always been this way for the two of us.
我们一直以来都像这样
Satou, I want that!
佐藤 我想要那个
One shot.
一次
That's 500 yen.
500圆
Rather than ruining our relationship,
我觉得与其破坏现在的关系
keeping things the way they are now isn't too bad.
维持现状也不错
However...
但是…
It'll work.
行得通
The mood is just right. I know it's going to work.
看这个气氛…感觉行得通
I... I want you to know that...
我…我对你…
It's so beautiful.
好漂亮
It's wonderful
太好了
to be watching this with you.
能和你一起看
Me too.
我也是
Satou.
佐藤
There is a secret
有一件事我一直保密
I could never bring myself to tell you.
无法说出口
Hold on, what's going on?
这是什么发展
Does it mean...
这个
It can't be...
该不会是…
I...
我…
I want you to know...
我也对你…
I'm moving away.
要搬家了
When?
什么时候
Tomorrow.
明天
I'm going back to Gramps' hometown.
我们要回去爷爷的故乡
It's somewhere very far away.
是很远的地方
You can't be serious!
不会吧
Satou.
佐藤
Thanks for tonight.
今天谢谢你陪我
Hime.
小姬
I...
我…
I'm so glad I could watch the fireworks with you.
能和你一起看烟火真是太好了
And the festival too.
还有庆典
And the doll you got me.
和玩偶
Do you really have to move away?
你无论如何都要搬家吗
In the end,
我在最后
you gave me a wonderful night to remember.
真的留下了很美好的回忆
Goodbye.
再见了
Hime!
小姬
Hime...
小姬…
She is leaving for somewhere far away.
她说是很远的地方
But where exactly is that?
到底要去哪里呢
Now that I think about it,
仔细想想
I thought I knew everything about her, but I actually knew nothing.
我一直以为自己很了解小姬 但其实什么都不知道
Even the day when I first met her.
就连遇见小姬那时的事也是
It felt like...
好像…
That's right.
没错
Something extraordinary must have happened that night!
好像发生过…什么不可思议的事
Hime!
小姬
Don't go!
不要走
So you do remember.
原来你还记得啊
In that case, you must know
既然如此 你应该明白吧
I lied about moving away.
搬家只是谎话
I'm leaving for a world
我要去的地方
that is entirely different from yours.
是与这里不同的世界
I'm getting married.
我要结婚了
After all, I am a princess.
因为我是公主
It's inevitable.
这是无可奈何的事
Hold... Hold on!
等…等一下
So this is truly the farewell.
所以这是真正的道别
Farewell, Satou.
再见 佐藤
I had a great time here.
我过得很开心
Hime!
小姬
What did I come here for?
我是为了什么才来这里的
At this point, am I supposed to just watch her leave?
都这个时候了 却只是目送她离开吗
No!
不对吧
In that case...
既然如此…
Overthinking won't do me any good.
东想西想也没用
Princess Nokanatika,
诺卡那堤卡公主
Krystal Novaty Nokanatika,
克莉丝朵·诺巴提·诺卡那堤卡
the Second Prince of Gisaras,
基萨拉斯第二王子
-Marmarugias Gisaras, -Who is that man?
-马尔玛利基亚斯·基萨拉斯 -那是谁啊
-you shall now become husband and wife... -He appeared right after the princess.
-两位现在将以戒指结为夫妻 -好像是跟在公主后面来的
What is this place?
这里是…
With your sacred kiss...
请用神圣之吻…
Who are you?
什么人
Hime!
小姬
Satou...
佐藤
Princess Krystal, who is he?
克莉丝朵公主 他是…
Stand down!
退下
Help!
不要啊
It's an Abyssal Creature!
是深渊的魔物
As expected, it's come to take the princess' life!
果然来取公主的性命了啊
-It was the right call -Great Sage Alabaster!
-之前先把公主藏在异界是对的 -贤者阿拉巴斯塔大人
-to hide the princess -It's the Great Sage!
-是大贤者
-in another world. -Great Sage Alabaster!
-之前先把公主藏在异界是对的 -阿拉巴斯塔大人
Hyah!
跳
Hime's grandpa?
小姬爷爷?
Satou? What are you doing here?
佐藤 你怎么会在这里
As expected, we need the Ring of Light.
果然…不能没有光之戒
Krystal!
克莉丝朵
Give the prince the Ring of Light!
快点把光之戒给王子
Satou!
佐藤
I have a bad feeling about this...
情况好像很不妙
Are you kidding me?
不会吧
So, you've made your decision, Princess Krystal.
原来是这样啊 克莉丝朵公主
Your Excellency, use this sword!
阁下 用这个吧
Impressive.
好厉害
This is a real sword.
是真正的剑
Wait, it's cool and all,
不对…是很厉害没错啦
but how am I supposed to fight that monster?
但我要怎么对付这种东西
Satou, watch out!
佐藤 小心后面
I still quite get it,
虽然搞不清楚状况
but this must be the right move!
总之只要这么做就行了吧
Huh?
奇…怪
Good morning, Satou.
早安 佐藤
Where am I?
这是哪里
The royal couple's bedchamber.
是国王夫妻的寝室
Couple?
夫妻?
Well, we didn't do it, didn't we?
因为我们不是做了吗
The kiss of oath.
誓约之吻
We... We did it!
做…做了
That means Hime really does...
也就是说 小姬果然对我…
Actually, I was supposed to marry that prince.
其实我本来应该和那位皇子结婚的
But I barely know the guy.
可是我跟他又不熟
I didn't want to marry someone like him.
也不想和那样的人结婚
Then, I saw a familiar face.
然后看到眼前有一张熟悉的脸
So I couldn't help it...
不自觉就…
What?
不自觉?
So...
所以啊
Sorry.
对不起
I made you my hero.
我选择你当勇者了
They say he is the Ring King.
听说那个人就是戒王
He seems to have come from a different world.
他好像是从别的世界来的
He was amazing!
他真的很厉害
With a single swing of the Sword of Light, he cut the Abyssal Creature in half!
用光之剑一击 就把深渊的魔物砍成两半
The wedding was supposed
那场结婚仪式
to fortify the relationship between the Empire and the Kingdom of Light.
原本是为了让光之国 和帝国建立关系的
When His Majesty learns about this,
要是皇帝陛下得知这个消息
I bet he'll be furious.
肯定会非常生气
The man chosen by the Ring Princess
光戒公主选择的人
is the Ring King, the saviour of this world.
就是拯救世界的戒王
Both he and I
我…还有他
are merely following our legacy to save the world.
都只是遵从救世的传承
It has nothing to do with what my father and the Empire think.
这应该与父皇的意志 和帝国的想法无关
The Second Prince is too boastful for his own good.
区区一个第二皇子还敢说大话
That's enough.
差不多可以了吧
You said you wanted to have an audience with His Majesty.
是你们说想拜见国王陛下
It's the only reason I made the time to meet you.
所以我才像这样腾出时间
Plenty of people are waiting in line to see His Majesty.
还有很多人等着见国王呢
All right, come with me.
好了 请到这边来
Defeat the Abyss!
击退深渊
-Ring King will bring light to Arnulus! -Ring King! Princess Krystal!
-替亚努鲁斯带来光明的戒王驾到 -戒王…克莉丝朵公主…
Okay, Satou,
好了 佐藤
say something.
你还不快点说些什么
Ring King! Ring King!
戒王 戒王…
Everyone has been waiting for the arrival of the new Ring King.
大家都在期盼戒王再次到来
-You're the beacon of hope for this world. -Ring King!
-你就是这个世界的希望 -戒王 戒王…
You should answer their anticipation.
必须回应大家的期待
I am...
我是…
I am Ring King Satou!
戒王佐藤
I've travelled from another world to save your world!
从异世界来拯救这个世界的
I'm your hero!
勇者
I think I got carried away.
我好像太得意忘形了
Hime.
小姬
Hey! Satou!
那个 佐藤
What... What are you...
你…你怎么会
It can't be helped.
有什么办法
We are officially married.
因为我们已经算是新婚夫妻了
Stop looking this way!
不准看这边
Sorry, Satou.
对不起 佐藤
I knew this would happen if I gave you the ring.
我明明知道把戒指交给你 就会变成这样
Why do you bring that up now?
为什么突然这么说
You were never part of this.
这件事明明跟你没关系
It's my fault that...
你却因为我…
I'm okay with this.
我不要紧的
See, it's already summer break.
你看 接下来就放暑假了
Besides,
而且
I'm the husband chosen by the Ring Princess herself.
我是被光戒公主选上的丈夫
I'm the Ring King.
戒王
Right?
没错吧
It's not wrong...
是这样没错
It's not like you get to leave this place.
再说你也不能离开这里吧
I'm from this world.
因为我是这个世界的人
But you, on the other hand...
可是佐藤你…
In that case, I'm staying as well.
那我也要待在这里
That monster from yesterday was after you and the ring you carried.
昨天的怪物是冲着你和戒指来的吧
Since I'm the only one who can keep you safe,
既然只有我能做到这件事
I'll never leave you.
那我会待在你身边
Her hair colour is weird.
好奇怪的发色
I bet she's a delinquent.
她是不良少女
Delinquent!
不良少女
Just ignore her.
还是别理她吧
Satou...
佐藤
Yeah...
果然…
You've always been so cool.
你从以前开始就很帅呢
Nothing.
没什么
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hey!
你在看什么
So... Sorry!
对…对不起
Let me be clear.
我先跟你说清楚
The royal families' weddings are nothing more than a formality.
王族的结婚只不过是形式
I made you my husband by accident.
我只是不小心选你当丈夫的
You don't have to feel responsible for anything.
你真的不用觉得自己有责任
I know. However...
嗯 不过…
I'm glad you chose me
虽然是不小心 但我还是很高兴
even though it was an accident.
对你选了我这件事
You must really like me a lot.
你真的很喜欢我呢
Sure.
对啊
You like me as a friend, right?
是作为朋友的喜欢吧
Of course, you are my most important
当然 你是我最重要的…
friend.
朋友
I see.
这样啊
What... What's going on?
怎…怎么了
Ring King...
戒王…
The Ring King is here!
戒王来了
Over here.
在这边…
Were you two having an intimate moment?
两位刚刚正在缠绵吗
We haven't done it yet!
我们还没做
We haven't?
还没?
Your Majesty.
戒王陛下
We are under attack by several Abyssal Creatures.
有多只深渊的魔物跑来攻击
The monster you slew was probably a scout.
前几天的那一只也许只是斥候
Please lend us your strength.
请您助我们一臂之力
You need me...
要我…
This is insane!
太勉强了
Satou has no combat skills whatsoever!
佐藤根本不知道怎么战斗
That won't change the fact that he must fight.
即使如此 他也必须战斗
Not as long as he has the ring.
只要他还持有那只戒指
Is that clear?
懂吗
You can't be serious!
不会吧
Sure. You can count on me.
好 交给我吧
Please use this.
请用这个
The Ring of Light is Evil's Bane.
光之戒是破邪之戒
It gives everything you touch the Banishing Light.
能赋予你拿到的所有东西驱魔之光
Its wielder will be blessed with tremendous power.
让戒指的主人得到力量
In other words,
换句话说
this is the ring that will create the strongest weapons against the Abyss.
这是能制造出打倒深渊的 最强武器的戒指
I don't know much about this world's situation.
我不清楚这个世界的情况
However,
但是
I know Hime's life is at stake.
我知道这件事攸关小姬的性命
That is why I will do my best to help.
既然如此 我也会尽我所能帮忙
Go, Ring King Satou!
上吧 戒王佐藤
Vanquish the evil beings! Save our world from turmoil!
击退邪恶之徒 拯救这个世界
Stay safe, my love.
慢走 亲爱的
Certainly.
好
I'll be right back.
我去去就回